{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Large parasites such as helminthes may be killed extracellularly by the action of", "opta": "basophils", "optb": "monocytes", "optc": "eosinophils", "optd": "neutrophils", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct for CD8 T cells?", "opta": "CD8 T cells only recognize virus-infected cells", "optb": "CD8 T cell receptor recognizes epitopes that are also commonly recognized by B cells", "optc": "In the thymus, CD8 T cells undergo positive selection only, whereas CD4 T cells undergo negative selection only", "optd": "CD8 T cells can kill individual virus-infected cells in a contact dependent fashion", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Passive immunization is done for", "opta": "tuberculosis", "optb": "diphtheria", "optc": "enteric fever", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct for isoantigens?", "opta": "They are antigens found in all members of different species", "optb": "They are antigens found in some members of a species", "optc": "They are antigens found in all members of a species", "optd": "They are antigens found in some members of different species", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Numerous antibodies can be prepared, against one antigen, each binds to unique epitopes. How is this antibody diversity generated?", "opta": "By rearrangements of the DNA encoding the variable regions of the heavy and light chains", "optb": "By the combination of different heavy and light chains that form the antigen binding site", "optc": "Antibody proteins can physically change their shape to bind different epitopes", "optd": "Both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following expresses CD3 surface antigen?", "opta": "Granulocytes", "optb": "T cells", "optc": "Monocytes", "optd": "B cells", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Polymorphonuclear leukocytes (or PMNs)", "opta": "can be attracted to the site of an infection following activation of complement", "optb": "are derived from bone marrow stem cells", "optc": "are a type of phagocyte that can engulf and kill bacteria", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Major Histo Compatibility Complex (MHC) is a collection of genes arrayed on", "opta": "chromosome 21 in man, chromosome 6 in mice", "optb": "chromosome 6 in man, chromosone 21 in mice", "optc": "chromosome 17in man, chromosome 6 in mice", "optd": "chromosome 6 in man, chromosome 17 in mice", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "CD8 surface antigen is present in", "opta": "cytotoxic T cells", "optb": "suppresssor T cells", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Treatment with bacterial endotoxins results blast formation in", "opta": "B cells", "optb": "T cells", "optc": "monocytes", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cytotoxic T-cells can be recognized by which of the following cell surface marker?", "opta": "CD4", "optb": "CD7", "optc": "CD8", "optd": "CD9", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not an antigen-presenting cell (or APC)?", "opta": "B cell", "optb": "Polymorphonuclear leukocyte (or PMN)", "optc": "Dendritic cell", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chemically an antigen may be", "opta": "lipid", "optb": "protein", "optc": "polysaccharide", "optd": "any of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "T cell receptors (or TCR) on CD4+ T cells", "opta": "recognize peptides not associated with MHC molecules", "optb": "recognize peptides associated with MHC class I molecules", "optc": "recognize peptides associated with MHC class II molecules", "optd": "are secreted out into the environment to bind antigens", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following proteins would not need localization signal?", "opta": "A nuclear protein", "optb": "A cytosolic protein", "optc": "A protein bound to the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) membrane", "optd": "A cell surface protein", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Following are the defenses of the colon except", "opta": "sIgA", "optb": "fast flow rate", "optc": "dense resident microbiota", "optd": "mucus", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Natural killer cells are involved in", "opta": "tumour rejection", "optb": "allograft rejection", "optc": "non-specific killing of virus transformed target cells", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following(s) is/are the determinants of antigenicity?", "opta": "Chemical nature", "optb": "Size of the antigen", "optc": "Foreignness", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "All T Cells are CD4+", "optb": "An epitope can have multiple antigens", "optc": "T Cell receptors are generated by random assortment of gene cassettes", "optd": "MHC Class II molecules are generated by random assortment of gene cassettes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Immunity is not long lasting to", "opta": "influenza", "optb": "whooping cough", "optc": "diphtheria", "optd": "mumps", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lysozyme is present in", "opta": "sweat", "optb": "Cerebro spinal fluid (CSF)", "optc": "urine", "optd": "saliva", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Macrophages are professional antigen- presenting cells. The protein molecule through which they present antigen in human is", "opta": "actin", "optb": "interleukin", "optc": "HLA", "optd": "CD8", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The role of the M cell is to", "opta": "trap virus in mucus and prevent entry", "optb": "induce apoptosis in virus-infected small intestinal epithelia cells", "optc": "pass bacteria or virus to underlying macrophages for processing and presentation of antigen", "optd": "they use their cilia to propel mucus out of the small intestine", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is false regarding B cells?", "opta": "B cells can undergo class switching and produce a different antibody type", "optb": "B one marrow stem cells migrate to the thymus and develop into B cells", "optc": "B cells synthesize antibodies and put them on their cell surface", "optd": "B cells that recognize high concentrations of antigens (self) in the absence of other signals undergo apoptosis in the bone marrow", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}